# Vitaly Sazanovich

Delft, South Holland, Netherlands

vitaly.sazanovich@gmail.com

+31647148658

linkedin.com/in/vitalysazanovich

# Summary

I have been working as a software developer for the last 18 years. Projects were mostly designed for the Internet and implemented in Java. Recently I started programming in TypeScript (Angular), Kotlin and Groovy.

I enjoy programming, here is my profile on GitHub: https://github.com/geniot

Some of my hobby/pet projects:

https://elex.mobi - dictionary server with full-text search and responsive ui https://octavian.app - learning app for Roland V-accordions, digital piano https://github.com/geniot/indexed-tree-map - enhanced java.util.TreeSet https://github.com/geniot/jnovelist - writer's novel management system, integrated with Git

# **Experience**



## Full Stack Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services Jul 2021 - Present (1 year +)



## 🛅 Full Stack Engineer

KLM Royal Dutch Airlines

Jul 2021 - Present (1 year +)

Planning & Control (May 2022 - current)

Project Aurora is a new schedule management and adjustment system written in Kotlin, Java, Groovy, TypeScript (Angular). It is designed to host schedule information of KLM's flights and later other airlines. The distribution service is designed to serve this information to hundreds of consumers.

Using Gradle, Kafka, Postgresgl, Cloud Object Storage. Architecture: microservices. Deployment: K8s. My achievements so far: migrated prod deployment to the new cluster, implemented a few user stories.

Learn & Evolve Department (July 2021 - April 2022)

Implemented integrations between KLM HR services, CornerStone, Moodle, AG5. Used Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, REST services; Bamboo, K8s, Pivotal Cloud Foundry (PCF). Did quite a few DevOps tasks: analysis of resources usage within the cluster, project configuration, console log analysis. Improved code quality using Sonar hints. Migrated deployments to new K8s cluster. Wrote mock tests following code coverage hints.

# Full Stack Engineer

**European Patent Office** 

Jun 2011 - Jun 2021 (10 years 1 month)

Project: Espacenet Worldwide Search

https://www.epo.org/searching-for-patents/technical/espacenet.html

Technologies/tools: JBoss, Apache, Spring, Maven, JQuery, JSP, Selenium, JUnit, Jenkins, Confluence, SVN/Git, React.

Implemented new features, fixed bugs, wrote tests, released and deployed the project, maintained documentation.

Project: OPS (from 3/2017 till current)

https://www.epo.org/searching-for-patents/data/web-services/ops.html

Technologies/tools: REST services, JBoss, Apache, Spring, Maven, RestEasy, JUnit, Jenkins,

Confluence, SVN/Git, XML, JSON

Implemented new features, fixed bugs, wrote tests, released and deployed the project, maintained documentation.

Project: New Espacenet (3 months in 2017)

https://worldwide.espacenet.com/ Technologies/tools: ReactJS, npm.

Implemented a query builder prototype using a third-party component.

Projects: TFLY, Di+, CPC, CCD (from 2011)

CPC browser: https://worldwide.espacenet.com/patent/cpc-browser

CCD: http://ccd.fiveipoffices.org/CCD-2.2.1/ TFLY and DI+ are used internally by examiners.

These 3 projects are wirtten in JavaScript (JQuery). I have maintained them for many years: occasional bug fixes / improvements, deployments to different environments.

Project: LTA, LTA-CMS (from 2011)

Internal service for setting app settings in different environments.

Technologies/tools: JBoss, Apache, Alfresco, Spring, Maven, JSP, Jenkins, Confluence, SVN/Git Fixed bugs, migrated to new environments (JVM, JBoss), released and deployed the project, maintained documentation.

Project: Data-Loader (2 months in 2019)

Internal component (part of another project) used for loading data into a database.

Technologies/tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Spring Boot, Maven, Jenkins, Git. Migrated this project to Kubernetes and Docker. (EPO's own data center).

## freelance software developer

#### freelance

Sep 2007 - May 2011 (3 years 9 months)

worked as a freelance software developer with a number of different American startups related to ad serving (http://www.inadco.com, http://www.brilig.com, http://www.payparade.com, http://www.dijipop.com)

#### software engineer

#### PayPod

Oct 2006 - Aug 2007 (11 months)

designed and implemented an ad server for an Indian startup with American venture capital

# software developer

**Coherent Solutions** 

Mar 2006 - Sep 2006 (7 months)

implemented new features, support and maintenance for one of the customers called Gearworks (now http://www.xora.com/)

## software engineer, project manager

Generation P

Sep 2004 - Mar 2006 (1 year 7 months)

Played different roles (concept, use-cases, design, implementation, time/resource management) on different projects in this dynamic company.

# product/sales manager

Wargaming

Aug 2002 - Mar 2004 (1 year 8 months)

Helped to improve and sell a program used for serving banner ads on the internet in the company's division called AdRevolver.

#### **Education**



# Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

Software Engineering

2008 - 2010



# Minsk State Linguistic University

Bachelor's degree

1997 - 2002

#### Skills

Online Advertising • Start-ups • Ad Serving • Software Development • Agile Methodologies • JavaScript • MySQL • Spring • Java Enterprise Edition • XML